# James Simon

**Active Selling Kitchen & Bath Co-worker** 

612.236.7797

notminebydesign@gmail.com

james.simon2@ikea.com

History of developing successful sales strategies and customer experience that cultivates brand loyalty. Strong background in retail sales.

**Process planning and implementation** driven by a constant desire for improvement through iteration with a focus on streamlining and strengthening.

**Honed relationship-building skills** and experience working collaboratively with external contractors, customers and customer-facing sales staff.

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **Kitchen Installation Services Specialist**

IKEA Twin Cities, Bloomington, MN 2013-2017

Promoted amidst a department in significant transition, with changes in entire product line, service provider, countertop provider, and management team. Given opportunity to work in tandem with new sales management team to revitalize sales strategy and external contractors through collaboration, lateral thinking, sales tracking and best working practices.

- Sales Growth of kitchen services 13% over last 2 fiscal years.
- Turned kitchen services from the highest cause of complaint to highest rated portion of the total kitchen experience.
- Part of team responsible for training entire site in new sales system.

#### Certified Kitchen Seller/Active Selling Kitchen & Bath Coworker

IKEA Twin Cities, Bloomington, MN 2011-2014, 2017-Present

Coached and assisted customers in planning their kitchens in a fast pace retail environment. Drove sales through intimate product knowledge, passion and the ability to discern customer desires. Gained recognition as a reliable troubleshooter and problem solver for any issue, ie. IT, customer, etc.

- Participated as part of a highly cooperative sales team that sold upwards of 20+ kitchens/day on peak days.
- Collaborated across function to improve routines for delivery and customer purchases.

## **SKILLS**

Proficient in Microsoft Office

Sales Development, Tracking and Forecasting

Sales Coaching

Vendor Relations and Mediation

Employee Training and Development

## **HIGHLIGHTS**

Kitchen services sales growth of 132% in 3 years

Complete turnaround of customer perception of kitchen service business

Coaching and educating team of 12 coworkers

Recognized as "September 2015 Coworker of the Month"

Active in tabletop gaming since 2010

# **EDUCATION**

A.A., Specialized Technology,

Thaddeus Steven College of Technology Lancaster, PA